Joseph Davidson

Full Stack Developer

054-454-7232 | josephdavidson1989@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn

Professional Summary

Detailed oriented and creative Full Stack developer with managerial experience. Able to work independently, self-teach, learn new concepts quickly, and produce high-standard, clean code.

Technical Skills

Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6/TypeScript), React, Mobx/Redux for state management.

Back-end: NodeJS, SQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Heroku (Dyno).

Other relevant skills: REST APIs, Unit-Testing, Git, Netlify.

Languages: Dutch: mother-tongue, English: fluent, Hebrew: conversational

Professional Experience

Full Stack Developer, Kululu

Nov 2022-Present

- Build new back and front-end features for a successful early stage startup using React, NodeJS and Firebase (TypeScript) that are used by thousands of users a month
- Completely refactored and rebuild the agent admin page from start to finish
- Independently researched, designed and developed highly sensitive API functionality from end to end
- Create a sandbox/dev environment for a better developer experience and team agility

IT Helpdesk Team Leader, Lightricks

Oct 2019- June 2022

- Lead a team of 4 helpdesk specialists who catered to the needs of nearly 500 employees
- Responsible for all new IT projects such as scouting the right software, purchasing devices, coordinating installation and training employees
- In-person execution of a brand new office in London for 50+ employees including computers, mobile devices, Zoom rooms, networks and more

Front-End Developer, Networx

Jan 2018- June 2019

- Successfully developed and implemented key features for the company's mobile app using the Ionic framework and Angular
- Refactored and redesigned the main webapp, utilizing advanced web technologies to significantly improve its performance, functionality, and aesthetics
- Implemented a highly effective notification system for agents within the CRM, leveraging advanced JavaScript and AJAX programming skills to deliver seamless and real-time communication.

Education

Full Stack Development Coding Bootcamp, Israel Tech Challenge

June 2022-Oct 2022

A training program designed to qualify full stack web developers. The program is a hands-on accelerator, which practices research and autonomous learning while emulating a real-life work environment.